const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",o=200,n=120,a=[{id:303,question:"Which of the following is a component of premium in insurance?",option:{a:"Margin",b:"Reserve",c:"Funds",d:"Capital"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:177,question:"Any circumstance that promotes the probability of a loss is called",option:{a:"Accident",b:"Hazard",c:"Loss",d:"Risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:309,question:"A new Nissan car valued at N= 350,000 was used to replace a Peugeot car with a sum insured N= 250.000 in private policy. The Peugeot car enjoys a 25% no claim discount. If the rate of premium is 11% and the no claim discount is transferred to the  new vehicle, what  would be the premium for the new Nissan car?",option:{a:"N= 20,625",b:"N= 27,500",c:"N= 28,875",d:"N= 38,500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:17,question:"How much premium will the insurer charge?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:90,question:"Any circumstance that promotes the probability of a loss is called",option:{a:"accident",b:"hazard",c:"loss",d:"risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:169,question:"A customer that suffers loss or sustain injury while using a business outfit that belongs to another perosn, can sue the property owner under -------------- insurance",option:{a:"Professional indemnity",b:"Public liability",c:"Employersâ€™ liability",d:"Personal accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:210,question:"Occurrence of an unplanned event is called",option:{a:"hazard",b:"loss",c:"risk",d:"speculation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:2,question:"One of the objectives of buying a term assurance policy is to",option:{a:"protect  dependants  in  case  of  death  of  the  life assured",b:"reduce financial burden of the life assured",c:"supplement retirement income  of  the  life  assured",d:"maximize savings from the life assured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:68,question:"The buyer of insurance product is",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:18,question:"How  much  premium  will  the  insurer  return  to  the insured?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:201,question:"Insurance is defined as",option:{a:"risking of loss",b:"pooling of risk",c:"gathering of risk",d:"waiving of risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:243,question:"The process of changing what is wrong in the policy is called",option:{a:"specification",b:"attestation clause",c:"rectification",d:"justification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:110,question:"Which of the following is non- insurable risk?",option:{a:"Gambling",b:"Accident",c:"Fire",d:"Theft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:8,question:"The evidence of the insurance contract is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"policy",c:"schedule",d:"endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:174,question:"A marine policy that provider cover for the construction of sea vessels is called --------- policy",option:{a:"Building",b:"Mixed",c:"Port",d:"Valued"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:222,question:"A contract that is contrary to public policy is",option:{a:"valid contract",b:"legal contract",c:"illegal contract",d:"voidable contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:24,question:"Ade insured his property for N= 350,000.00. The property is subject to average condition. He suffered a loss amounting to N= 30,000.00 with the value of the property at the time of loss to be N= 370,000.00. How much will the insurer pay?",option:{a:"N= 14,583.33",b:"N= 28,378.38",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 31,714.29"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:119,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Insurable risk",c:"Subrogation",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:145,question:"Factor that causes an exposure to injury, loss or damage is",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Hazard",c:"Peril",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:230,question:"one of these is a content of a proposal form",option:{a:"children of the proposer",b:"education of the proposer",c:"occupation of the proposer",d:"educational"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:216,question:"With assurance contract there is",option:{a:"uncertainly of reward",b:"certainty of reward",c:"certainty of occurrence",d:"uncertainty of occurrence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:173,question:"The following are types of life assurances,  except",option:{a:"annuity",b:"Endowment",c:"Hire purchase",d:"Whole life"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:306,question:"Which of the following is the function of a loss adjuster?",option:{a:"Ensures payment of adequate compensation",b:"Advises the insurer on claim",c:"Operates with unlimited authority",d:"Notifies insurer of the loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:190,question:"When an   insurer agrees   to   replace   irreparably damaged or stolen goods with similar type it is called",option:{a:"Reinstatement",b:"Cash",c:"Repairs",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:322,question:"The  person  that   transfers  risks  to  the  insurance company is called",option:{a:"a broker",b:"an insured",c:"an underwriter",d:"a loss adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:279,question:"A policy that covers the peril of the sea is",option:{a:"aviation",b:"marine",c:"life",d:"fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:296,question:"The maximum number of days allowed for a policy holder to pay his renewal premium after it has become due is called",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"conditions",c:"days of grace",d:"days of liberty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:11,question:"Which of the following is not a feature of insurable interest?",option:{a:"Loss suffered",b:"subject matter",c:"Legal relationship",d:"Financial value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:175,question:"Spreading of risk to ensure that no insurer is liquidated by the occurrence of a large loss is the concept of",option:{a:"Insurance",b:"Re insurance",c:"Renewal",d:"Treaty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:81,question:"The following are examples of bad moral hazard except",option:{a:"Fraudulent activities",b:"Carelessness",c:"Honesty",d:"Unreasonableness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:158,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Peril",b:"Hazard",c:"Loss",d:"Risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:343,question:"Which of the following activities is not involved in claims management?",option:{a:"Proof of loss",b:"Particulars of loss",c:"Premium calculation",d:"Primary investigation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:127,question:"Re-insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Re-insurer and insurer",b:"Re- insurance and insurance",c:"Co-insurer and insurer",d:"Insurance broker and re-insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:311,question:"Which  of  the  following  statements  is  true  about property insurance?",option:{a:"The probability that the event may occur",b:"The probability that the event will not occur",c:"The probability that the event may or may not occur",d:"The probability that the event must occur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:129,question:"The  payment  made  by  underwriter  as  a  form  of  	kindness  without  admission  of  liability  so  as  to maintain goodwill is known as ------------",option:{a:"Kindness payment",b:"Ex-gratia payment",c:"Favour payment",d:"Claim"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:76,question:"The following are insurable except",option:{a:"Marine",b:"Goods",c:"Gambling",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:224,question:"Risk that affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"pure risk",c:"fundamental risk",d:"static risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:100,question:"Unlawful breaking and entering into any premises or place of safe keeping is covered under which of these policies?",option:{a:"burglary",b:"business interruption",c:"employers liability",d:"public liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:219,question:"A seller of insurance product is",option:{a:"insurer",b:"promisor",c:"client",d:"insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:14,question:"Abandonment is mostly applicable to",option:{a:"marine insurance",b:"motor insurance",c:"fire insurance",d:"engineering insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:48,question:"A <em>revival clause</em> in a life policy will allow an insured to revive a policy that lapsed on account of nonpayment of premium, provided the insured",option:{a:"can prove he is sick at the time",b:"cannot fall sick after the policy",c:"can prove he is in good health",d:"can recover from the ill health"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:19,question:"A policy that combines cover for many perils as a single policy  to  suit  the  insurance  needs of  an insured is",option:{a:"accident policy",b:"protection policy",c:"paternal policy",d:"packaged policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:66,question:"Insured is likewise known as",option:{a:"insuree",b:"Insurer",c:"policy holder",d:"contractor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:131,question:"The prices set by the insurer for the insurance cover is known as",option:{a:"Due",b:"Levy",c:"Premium",d:"Charge"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:198,question:"A payment made by insurer as a form of sympathy to maintain goodwill is",option:{a:"Compensation payment",b:"Contract payment",c:"Charity payment",d:"Ex - gratia payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:257,question:"One of the following is legally used by the insured while the policy is being processed",option:{a:"indemnity form",b:"claim form",c:"cover note",d:"proposal form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:56,question:"A fundamental condition which must be filled  by the  insured for compensation is",option:{a:"warranty",b:"obligation",c:"interest",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:33,question:"George effected two personal accident policies. The first policy provides N= 25,000.00 cover for loss of limb. The second policy provides N= 30,000.00 cover for loss of limb. What is the total amount that  George  will receive in the event of a valid loss of limb claim?",option:{a:"N= 5,000.00",b:"N= 25,000.00",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 55,000.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:181,question:"To break or act contrary to a law or promise means",option:{a:"Breach",b:"Shake",c:"Confirm",d:"Disagreement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:69,question:"The seller of insurance product is",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Insured",c:"Broker",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:199,question:"The policy that provides protection for goods or cargoes and ships against the perils of the sea is",option:{a:"Fire",b:"Marine",c:"Aviation",d:"Credit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:109,question:"In the utmost good faith principle, the value of the subject matter should",option:{a:"Be over stated",b:"Understated",c:"Not be stated",d:"Not be overstated nor understated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:105,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance?",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Compensation",c:"Proximate cause",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:55,question:"A  statement  of  fact  that  the insured must have an interest in the object of the contract is called",option:{a:"warranty",b:"insurable interest",c:"subrogation",d:"object interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:332,question:"One of the benefits payable under personal accident insurance policy is",option:{a:"retirement benefit",b:"surrender benefit",c:"death benefit",d:"transfer benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:26,question:"An insurer who buys reinsurance cover is insured as",option:{a:"retrocession",b:"retrocedant",c:"cession",d:"cadent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:221,question:"A contract which has no legal effect is called",option:{a:"voidable contract",b:"legal contract",c:"void contract",d:"valid contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:277,question:"policy designed for the insured who is incapacitated to carry out normal duty is",option:{a:"medical expenses",b:"temporary disablement",c:"permanent disablement",d:"medical expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:267,question:"One of this is the consideration paid for insurance contract",option:{a:"fee",b:"cheque",c:"commission",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:338,question:"The amount charged when a ship overstays at the port under a marine contract is",option:{a:"penalty",b:"fine",c:"overcharge",d:"demurrage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:285,question:"The principle of maritime law which makes owners of ship and cargo share in a lost incurred voluntarily is",option:{a:"general average",b:"special average",c:"specific average",d:"particular average"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:290,question:"Marine insurance policy which covers all the ship or vessels belonging to one owner is",option:{a:"flect policy",b:"mixed policy",c:"value policy",d:"fixed policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:260,question:"If the insured has been fully indemnified, the insurers are entitled to take any advantage due to the insured. Principle of insurance involved is",option:{a:"insurable interest",b:"contribution",c:"indemnity",d:"subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:143,question:"The clauses in the policy which make alterations or additions to the information stated in the policy is known as",option:{a:"correction",b:"Modification",c:"Change",d:"Endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:45,question:"The consideration paid for insurance contract is",option:{a:"money",b:"commission",c:"premium",d:"fee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:112,question:"Hazard that deals with the human habits and character that arises from human attitude and the conduct of people is called",option:{a:"physical",b:"Moral",c:"Static",d:"Dynamic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:281,question:"The process of examining, accepting or rejecting risks and classifying the ones accepted is",option:{a:"underwriting",b:"policy",c:"procedures",d:"warranty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:298,question:"The cause of a loss is",option:{a:"peril",b:"hazard",c:"risk",d:"loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:292,question:"Speailative risks are",option:{a:"insurable risk",b:"non insurable risk",c:"financial risk",d:"non financial risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:88,question:"A miss statement of fact that is made by the insured or his broker to an underwriter during negotiation is called",option:{a:"annuity",b:"misrepresentation",c:"endorsement",d:"disclosure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:132,question:"The transfer of risk already undertaken from one insurance company to another is",option:{a:"Over insurance",b:"Re insurance",c:"Under insurance",d:"Group insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:245,question:"A reminder to the insured that this existing contract is due to expire is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"slip",c:"claim form",d:"renewal notice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:75,question:"The following risks are insurable except",option:{a:"particular",b:"pure",c:"static",d:"dynamic risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:282,question:"The periodic payment made by the insured to the insurer as financial cost of obtaining insurance",option:{a:"annuity",b:"premium",c:"claim",d:"dividend"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:82,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Peril",c:"Hazard",d:"Moral"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:299,question:"The party who proposes to the insurance company to insure his properly is called",option:{a:"offeree",b:"offeror",c:"acceptance party",d:"offer client"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:21,question:"The document that sets out the list of items covered in insurance is a",option:{a:"manifest",b:"bill of lading",c:"policy list",d:"policy specification or form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:182,question:"A professional officer of an insurance company whose duty among others is to calculate the premium to be 	paid by the insured is called",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Principal",c:"Actuarist",d:"Adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:333,question:"A  trade  group for insurance  companies in  Nigeria is called",option:{a:"Chartered Insurance Institute of Nigeria",b:"National Insurance Commission",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"Nigerian Insurers Association"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:329,question:"The  sum  insured  for  a  risk  is  N= 150,000  and  was accepted  for  fire  insurance at a rate of  0.25%. How much will the insured pay as a premium?",option:{a:"N= 125",b:"N= 375",c:"N= 500",d:"N= 875"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:44,question:"Insurers A and B cover a risk at the ratio of 2:5 for the sum insured of N= 1,800. How much would insurer  A get from the risk?",option:{a:"N= 1,285.00",b:"N= 771.00",c:"N= 514.00",d:"N= 180.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:108,question:"Which of the following is not a function of insurance?",option:{a:"Serves as collateral",b:"Encouraging saving",c:"Provides insecurity",d:"Reduces risks"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:46,question:"The alternative to seeking for surrender value in a life assurance contract is",option:{a:"automatic non - forfeiture",b:"revival condition",c:"paid-up policy",d:"standing order"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:209,question:"In insurance, uncertainty of loss means",option:{a:"hazard",b:"risk",c:"accident",d:"earthquake"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:57,question:"The object of an insurance policy is equally known as",option:{a:"insurance title",b:"insurance premium",c:"subject matter",d:"risk object"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:308,question:"A type of re - insurance  where  the re - insurer has  the option  to  accept  or  reject  any  risk  presented  for re-insurance is",option:{a:"stop loss",b:"facultative",c:"treaty",d:"excess of loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:94,question:"Payment of claims  in  liability  insurance are usually made in favour of",option:{a:"insurance agent",b:"a third party",c:"employees",d:"employers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:95,question:"The person  that  brings  an insurance  contract  into existence between  the principal and third party  is a/an",option:{a:"agent",b:"bailee",c:"contractor",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:251,question:"Insurance premium depends on the",option:{a:"amount of profit to be made by the insurer",b:"various insurance companies in a place",c:"extent of the possible loss and the frequency of risk",d:"supply and demand"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:236,question:"Which of the method below can be used to provide indemnity in the event of loss",option:{a:"moral advice",b:"resolution of policy",c:"cash payment",d:"professional encouragement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:113,question:"A peril is best defined as",option:{a:"Chance of a loss",b:"The occurrence of a loan",c:"The cause of a loss",d:"The result of a loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:153,question:"The provider of protection to an insurance  company against the excess risk it has given insurance covers is called",option:{a:"Assurer",b:"Insuring",c:"Reinsurer",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:312,question:"In a life assurance contract, when does  the  principle of insurable interest arise?",option:{a:"At the beginning of the contract",b:"At the time of claim",c:"At the middle of the contract",d:"At the time of payment of premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:316,question:"Educational endowment policy is designed to protect the interest of",option:{a:"father",b:"mother",c:"child",d:"uncle"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:344,question:"Life  assurance  contract is useful to a policyholder in the area of",option:{a:"production",b:"protection",c:"industrialization",d:"rehabilitation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:28,question:"Family income option in a life policy provides that",option:{a:"the beneficiary will be paid for life",b:"the beneficiary receives the policy sum",c:"interest will be added monthly",d:"salary will be paid to the insured until death"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:187,question:"The insurance principle which implies that a proof is required that the direct and immediate cause of the loss suffered was by the occurrence of the risk insured against is called",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Proximate cause",c:"Insurable interest",d:"Utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:213,question:"Insurance is a contract that is based on",option:{a:"possibility",b:"probability",c:"positivity",d:"negativity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:31,question:"A type of reinsurance where cession and acceptance is obligatory is",option:{a:"treaty",b:"captive",c:"facultative",d:"retrocession"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:176,question:"The person  that  brings  an  insurance  contract into existence  between  the principal  and  third  party is a/an",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Bailee",c:"Contractor",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:237,question:"A card used by motorist in the West African sub-region is called",option:{a:"insurance certificate",b:"insurance register",c:"insurance green card",d:"Ecowas brown card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:35,question:"Risk Net Insurance Brokers Limited placed a business with an insurance company, in return the broker will be entitled to",option:{a:"fees",b:"commission",c:"profit",d:"revenue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:166,question:"Another name for consequential loss is",option:{a:"Stop loss",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Business interruption insurance",d:"Excess loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:178,question:"Indemnity is provided through the following media except",option:{a:"Cash",b:"Commission",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Repair"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:25,question:"A method of providing indemnity in the event of loss is",option:{a:"cash payment",b:"professional advice",c:"resolution of dispute",d:"resolution of policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:121,question:"Insurance is necessary because of the need to",option:{a:"Pool resources together",b:"Meet uncertainties in future",c:"Make profit",d:"Lend money to individual"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:253,question:"Payment by the insurer to the insured out of sympathy is known as",option:{a:"utmost good faith",b:"proximate cause",c:"peril",d:"ex-gratia payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:335,question:"Who  among  the  following  is  an  employer  of  loss adjuster?",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:317,question:"A clause in an insurance policy that makes a claim jointly payable to the policyholder and the third party is",option:{a:"claim clause",b:"mortgagee clause",c:"mortgage clause",d:"joint liability clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:200,question:"Another name for an insured in a life insurance contract is",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Assured",c:"Assurer",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:30,question:"Which of the following policies is a peril covered under a standard fire policy?",option:{a:"Lightning",b:"Storm",c:"Civil commotion",d:"Escape of oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:102,question:"Insurable interest means",option:{a:"Interest gained on money in a bank",b:"Interest payable on a loan",c:"Financial interest a person has in something he expects to inherit",d:"The financial interest a person has in something of value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:154,question:"---------- is the evidence cover of the risk given to the insured by the insurer",option:{a:"Cover",b:"Policy",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:63,question:"The evidence of the contractual agreement between the insured and insurer is",option:{a:"policy",b:"proposal form",c:"insurance certificate",d:"cover note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:103,question:"Below are insurable policies except",option:{a:"Earthquake",b:"Fire",c:"Life",d:"Marine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:239,question:"The part of a policy form that shows the name and address of the company is known as",option:{a:"heading",b:"conclusion",c:"condition",d:"preamble"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:120,question:"An application form which is filled by anyone taking out an insurance policy is called",option:{a:"A policy form",b:"A claim form",c:"A proposal form",d:"Proximate cause form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:241,question:"Policy condition which are automatically applicable and not stated in the contract of agreement is known as",option:{a:"agreed condition",b:"agreed negotiation",c:"implied condition",d:"expressed condition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:42,question:"A voucher signed by the insured before collecting his claim is",option:{a:"money collect receipt",b:"discharge voucher",c:"payment receipt",d:"pay - in - slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:195,question:"Application by the insured to the insurer for the payment of money due under his contract of insurance is",option:{a:"Proof",b:"Evidence",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"}],t={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,t as default,e as message,o as status,i as subject,n as total};
